# **Bruno Martins**

# Junior Software Developer | Lab Technician

Location: Barcelos, Portugal Phone: +351 962 915 768 Email: bruno@kazy.pt linkedin.com/in/bmrtins Website: kazy.pt

### **PROFILE**

Junior software developer with 5+ years of laboratory experience using self-developed tools to perform automated data processing and analysis. Developed apps using **Python** to automate repeatable everyday tasks as well as work-related apps to improve productivity. Passionate about learning new programming languages and related technologies and developing responsive frontend web apps using **React** and **CSS**.

Fast learner and highly-motivated in multidisciplinary environments with both team-oriented and individual tasks.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Laboratory Technician, Matias & Araújo, S.A. • Barcelos, Nov. 2020 — Present

- Data input on **Tecnorama** automatic dye dispensing system.
- System maintenance and troubleshooting.
- Software automation improvements using Python.

**Laboratory Assistant (Part time)**, Microbiology Department, UTAD • Vila Real, Sep. 2018 — Jul. 2020 **Intern Laboratory Technician**, Cytogenetics Laboratory, CHTMAD • Vila Real, 2017

**Golf Course Marshal**, Pestana Golf Resort • Carvoeiro, 2015 — 2019

## **EDUCATION**

Master's degree in Biochemistry • UTAD, Set. 2021

Bachelor's degree in Biochemistry • UTAD, Jul. 2018

## **PROGRAMMING SKILLS**

React (incl. Hooks, Context, Routes), JavaScript (incl. Promises & Async/Await), HTML 5, CSS 3 (incl. Flexbox, Grid), MySQL, Firebase (incl. Cloud Firestore, Auth), Python, Git

### **CERTIFICATES**

The Ultimate MySQL Bootcamp: Go from SQL Beginner to Expert by Colt Steele • Udemy, Jul. 2023

Build Web Apps with React & Firebase by Shaun Pelling • Udemy, May 2023

**Build Responsive Real-World Websites with HTML and CSS** by Jonas Schmedtmann • Udemy, Mar. 2023

Modern JavaScript (Complete guide, from Novice to Ninja) by Shaun Pelling • Udemy, Nov. 2022

### LANGUAGES

Portuguese (native), English (excellent), Spanish (intermediate)

## **OTHERS**

XIII ENEBIOQ Organizing Committee – Head of Publishing Department • Vila Real, Jul./Aug. 2021

• Event's website development.